Guide to the Muriel Draper Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1921-1976; Series IV; 3.25; (8 boxes)
  - ORGANIZATIONS AND CAUSES
    - American Society for Technical Aid to Spanish Democracy, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 755)
    - Art Center, 1926 Jan, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 756)
    - Artistic organizations, 1924-38, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 757)
    - Basque Delegation, 1937, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 758)
    - Block Community Organization, 1932 Mar 12 (Box 23, Folder 759)
    - Communist Party of the United States of America, 1937-38 (Box 23, Folder 760)
    - Congress of American Women
      - Commission on Child Care, report, 1947 Jun (Box 23, Folder 761)
      - Committee on Action for Peace and Democracy, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 762-63)
      - Committee on Action for Peace and Democracy, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 764)
      - [Committee?] resolutions, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 765)
      - Constitution, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 766)
      - Correspondence, 1945-50, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 767-77)
      - Magazine clippings, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 778)
      - Memoranda [to public officials] (Box 24, Folder 779)
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-47 (Box 24, Folder 780)
      - Miscellaneous printed material, 1946, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 781)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 782-83)
      - Notebook, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 784)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 785-91)
      - Notes on Paris Conference, [1946?] (Box 24, Folder 792)
      - Reports, 1951 May, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 793-94)
      - Reports to the WIDF, 1945-48 (Box 25, Folder 795-96)
      - Resolution, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 797)
      - Speeches, [1949?], n.d. (Box 25, Folder 798-800)
      - Un-American Activities Committee, 1949-50, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 801)
      - Woman Power, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 802)
    - Downtown Music School, 1937-38 (Box 25, Folder 803)
    - Film and Speakers Buro, 1937 May (Box 25, Folder 804)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1937 Mar 25 (Box 25, Folder 805)
    - Friends of Spanish Democracy, 1936 (Box 25, Folder 806)
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Battalion, 1937 Jun 15 (Box 25, Folder 807)
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 808)
    - F[riends] [of the] S[oviet] U[nion], plan for organization (Box 25, Folder 809)
    - Gallup Civil Rights Committee, 1938 (Box 25, Folder 810)
    - Independent Citizens' Committee of the Arts, Sciences, and Professionals, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 811)
    - International Theatre Exposition, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 812)
    - League of American Writers
      - Bulletins, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 813)
      - Letters to the Editor, 1938, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 814)
      - Manuscript sale flyer, 1938 Mar (Box 25, Folder 815)
      - Meeting notice, membership cards, and receipts, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 816)
      - National Congress of American Writers, schedule, programs, and report, 1937, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 817)
      - Second International Congress, bulletin, 1937 Aug (Box 25, Folder 818)
    - League for Southern Labor, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 819)
    - The Little Review, [1928?] (Box 25, Folder 820)
    - N.A.A.C.P., 1926-29, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 821)
    - National Committee for People's Rights, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 822)
    - National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners, 1937-38 (Box 25, Folder 823)
    - National Committee on Rural Social Planning, 1937 Apr (Box 25, Folder 824)
    - National Committee to Aid Striking Miners Fighting Starvation, 1932, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 825)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1945-51, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 826)
    - National Federation New World Discussion Clubs, 1937, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 827)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 828)
    - O'Connell Peace Act, 1938 Apr 6 (Box 25, Folder 829)
    - "Political Organizations", 1931-47, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 830)
    - Russian Students' Christian Association, 1922, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 831)
    - S.F.P.C., membership and committee lists, 1935-36 (Box 25, Folder 832)
    - The Taxi Patrons' Protective Society, 1926 Feb 1 (Box 25, Folder 833)
    - Technocracy, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 834)
    - Theatre Committee for Aid to Spanish Democracy, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 835)
    - Women's Community Forum, 1947 Apr (Box 25, Folder 836)
    - Women's International Democratic Federation
      - Article, 1946 Jun (Box 25, Folder 837)
      - Conference notes, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 838)
      - Manifestos, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 839)
      - Report, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 840)
      - Resolutions, 1946, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 841)
    - Women's National Peace Delegation, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 842)
- Oversize
  Oversize material has been placed here in series order.
  - Tobey, Mark, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 843)
  - Artwork, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 844-46)
  - Greeting card, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 847)
  - Photographs
    - Alington, Lord Napier, [1935?] (Box 26, Folder 848)
    - Douglas, Norman, 1935 Jun 23 (Box 26, Folder 849)
    - Draper, Muriel, 1934 Jul 30 (Box 26, Folder 850)
    - Draper, Paul (photograph by Emelie Danielson), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 851)
    - Garden, Mary, 1927, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 852-53)
    - Bust of Paul Draper (photograph by Emelie Danielson), statue, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 854)
    - Houses, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 855)
    - Window display (Box 26, Folder 856)
    - Unidentified (photograph by Margaret Bourke-White), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 857)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 858)
    - Corley, Donald: ink drawing ("Prelude for Black Keys"), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 859)
    - Tobey, Mark: pencil sketch, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 860)
  - Hat (Box 27, Box 861)
  - Hat (Box 28, Box 862)
  - Hat (Box 29, Box 863)
  - Hat (Box Box 30, Box 864)